
const cards = [
  {
    id: 0,
    front:
      "Start!",
    back: "Press next to start the flashcards",
  },
  {
    id: 1,
    front:
      "Who was the founder of Standard Oil and became the world’s richest man?",
    back: "John D. Rockefeller",
  },
  {
    id: 2,
    front:
      "Which businessman controlled America’s railroads and shipping industry?",
    back: 'Cornelius “Commodore” Vanderbilt',
  },
  {
    id: 3,
    front: "Who revolutionized car manufacturing with the assembly line?",
    back: "Henry Ford",
  },
  {
    id: 4,
    front:
      "Which financier helped stabilize the U.S. economy during financial crises and formed U.S. Steel?",
    back: "J.P. Morgan",
  },
  {
    id: 5,
    front:
      "Who built a steel empire and later became famous for philanthropy, building libraries and universities?",
    back: "Andrew Carnegie",
  },
  {
    id: 6,
    front:
      "What was Rockefeller’s main strategy for dominating the oil industry?",
    back:
      "Horizontal integration; buying out competitors to control the entire market",
  },
  {
    id: 7,
    front:
      "How did Henry Ford make cars affordable for everyday Americans?",
    back:
      "By using mass production and assembly lines to drastically cut manufacturing costs",
  },
  {
    id: 8,
    front:
      "What major company did J.P. Morgan purchase from Andrew Carnegie in 1901?",
    back: "Carnegie Steel; which he turned into U.S. Steel",
  },
  {
    id: 9,
    front:
      "What transportation network did Vanderbilt first build his fortune on before railroads?",
    back: "Steamboats and shipping",
  },
  {
    id: 10,
    front:
      "What is Andrew Carnegie’s famous philosophy about wealth called?",
    back:
      '“The Gospel of Wealth”: the belief that the rich should use their money to help society',
  },
];

export default cards;
